<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.giddyupmultisport.com/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.giddyupmultisport.com/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.giddyupmultisport.com/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>Giddy Up Multisport - News</title>
  <updated>2019-02-12T09:04:00-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Giddy Up Multisport</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.giddyupmultisport.com/blogs/news/yes-winter-swimming-is-a-must</id>
    <published>2019-02-12T09:04:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-12T09:04:48-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.giddyupmultisport.com/blogs/news/yes-winter-swimming-is-a-must"/>
    <title>YES, Winter swimming is a must!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Robin Barsantee</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><span>YES. WINTER SWIMMING IS A MUST.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></span></p>
<p>According to Coach Michellie and Coach Robin, the winter months are the perfect opportunity to work on your swim technique. It tends to be the weakest of the three disciplines for many triathletes. While the swim is the shortest in length during a race, it can have quite an impact on your overall performance-however, significant gains can be made by working on the fundamentals of swimming. <br><span></span></p>
<p><span>Coach Michellie and Coach Robin</span><span> suggests you incorporate 2-3 swim sessions weekly into your workout plan – just enough to maintain your current swim fitness. The addition of a fourth session of just drills and technique focus is also advised. “It can have a dramatic impact, not just in terms of getting faster, but also more efficient; that translates into more energy for the bike and run,” Coach MJ said. She added that because triathletes are basically open water swimmers, having a strong and powerful stroke is necessary.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></span></p>
<p><span>When drills are the focus for your workouts, Our Coaches have their favorites. All triathletes typically need balance, rotation, and power drills. Sculling and flotation drills help with feel of the water and body position. Rotation drills promote bilateral breathing, a confidence builder when sunlight and choppy water in a race makes it difficult to breathe on one side. Finally, power drills like using paddles and bands assist in the development of better pull and push in the stroke.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;">COACH MJ &amp; ROBO’s TOP SWIM DRILLS <br><span></span></p>
<ol>
<li>
<span></span><span>Sculling – place your hands out in front of <br></span><span>you with your elbows up, head down in the water, and move hands to the side at head height and under your chest. <br> <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></span><span><br> </span>
</li>
<li>
<span></span><span>Flotation – push off the wall with your hands by your side, push down on your chest with a small kick, and breathe by rotating your hips; you should feel as though you are swimming over a barrel as you progress forward. <br> <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></span><span><br> </span>
</li>
<li>
<span></span><span>Rotation – swim on one side only, then switch; single-arm freestyle, or swim with a kick board vertically between your thighs to feel the board tap the water on each side. <br> </span><span><span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></span><span><br> </span>
</li>
</ol>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
